# Amit Kumar Mishra

Seeking a beginner role to enhance and explore my knowledge gained at IIIT, Bhubaneswar in the last two years. I am a passionate learner and always try to explore different fields. I have also been part of some open source programs like DevScript Winter of Code and GirlScript Summer of Code.



mamit7503@gmail.com

8688785464

in linkedin.com/in/amit-mishra-28122a193

github.com/Amit366

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Technology** International Institute of Information Technology, Bhubaneswar

06/2019 - Present

9.01

Courses CSE

#### Intermediate

FIITJEE Junior College, Visakhapatnam

04/2017 - 04/2019

97.2

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Web Developer Intern** AasPass

07/2021 - Present

Tasks

 Responsible for creating and maintaining the admin panel (frontend and backend) of the organization.

#### **Web Developer Intern and Project mentor** LetsGrowMore

06/2021 - Present

Tasks

- As a web intern I am assigned to work on building websites using react, HTML, CSS and JS.
- As a Project Mentor, I am the mentor for the project Daily Algo which is a DSA based project.

#### **Open Source Contributor** GirlScript Summer of Code

03/2021 - Present

Tasks

- Contributed to various projects like:
- NeoAlgo: Added different data structures and algorithms.
- NeoAlgo-Docs: Added documentations on various algorithms.
- Amazing-Python-Scripts: Added different python scripts which can be used in our daily lives like unzipping a zipped file, PDF to text converter and so on.
- Awesome-Javascript-Projects: Added few javascript projects.

#### **Open Source Contributor DevScript Winter of Code**

12/2020 - 02/2021

Tasks

- Contributed to various projects like:
- FireShort: Changed the entire UI of the login page.
- World-Covid-Tracker: Made it a Progressive Web App.
- idea-lab: Made it a Progressive Web App.

## **SKILLS**

Web development Active listening

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### Courier Website

- This is a team project where I worked on the backend and some part of frontend. In this website user can register themselves for courier services .
- Here the tech stack used are HTML, CSS and PHP.
- The link to the project: https://github.com/Amit366/CourierWebsite

- This app is a memes sharing app. The app has two buttons 'next' and 'share'. On clicking 'next' different memes are fetched from an API and 'share' button is used to share the memes on social media
- The tech stack used is Java.
- The link to the project: https://github.com/Amit366/MemesApp

#### Birthday Card App

- This is an app in which a happy birthday caption with an image is generated on typing the name of a person.
- The tech stack used is Java.
- The link to the project: https://github.com/Amit366/Birthday\_Card\_app

# **CERTIFICATES**

Fundamentals: Data, Data Everywhere

Course on basics of Data Analytics from Coursera

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

I participated in DevScript Winter of Code and secured sixth rank out of 2200 participants.

I participated in Cross Winter of Code and secured second rank out of 300 participants

# LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Teluau

Limited Working Proficiency

Limited Working Proficiency

# INTERESTS

Sports

Gaming